# IHOR OKSENTIUK FRONT-END

ihor.oksentiuk@gmail.com 067-289-75-17

**Portfolio** 

<u>Telegram</u>

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

Odesa, Lutsk, Ukraine / Remote + Office



Experienced Front-end developer with 1+ years in front-end. Skilled in HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, Typescript, Webpack, React, Angular, Node.js. Motivated, stress-resistant, and self-confident. Visual aesthetics has been a lifelong passion. I excel at solving intricate problems that yield visually appealing outcomes, enhancing lives. Opting for full-stack development stems from a curiosity about the complete process and a desire to excel in both frontend and backend. Proficiency in both allows me to execute holistic web app cycles, covering functionality, design, and database integration. I maintain positivity even during challenging or monotonous tasks, uplifting myself and those around me. Have an Intermediate English for communication in foreign teams.

# **SKILLS**

- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React, Redux, Redux Toolkit
- Next.js
- Angular, Angular Material
- Node.js, Express.js
- HTML, CSS (SCSS), Styled Components, Tailwind, BEM
- Wordpress
- GIT, Webpack
- English: Upper Intermediate
- Knowledge of SDLC & STLC
- Agile concepts knowledge (Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban) + Waterfall
- Bug & Task-managers: Jira, ClickUP, Trello
- RxJS
- SQL
- Figma

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Front-end developer Nov 2023 - Present Get IT Done Agency (post-project work)

- Developed adaptive landing pages and websites of various complexity levels based on WordPress (ACF, Elementor);
- Participated in team calls to discuss company goals and improvement methods;
- Approved and corrected design layouts for landing pages;
- Made edits, and improved existing websites and other projects.

# Front-end Developer Jan 2022 - Nov 2023 Self-employed

- Adhered to the company's workflow and reported on the status of tasks in google spreadsheet;
- Attended regular Zoom meetings with the team and actively worked in a team to achieve development goals;
- UI/UX Design, Responsive Design, JavaScript Development, Component-Based Architecture, Web Performance Optimization
- Server-Side Logic, API Development, Database Management;
- Testing and Debugging;
- · Version Control and Deployment;

#### Senior operational officer Nov 2019 - Oct 2021

State Fiscal Service of Odesa region

- Tax control and audits
- Detection of violations in the field of tax law
- Conducting inspections at enterprises
- · Consulting and informing

# **PROJECTS**

I want to present my latest projects here, but you can explore the full collection by visiting my portfolio.

# Gadgets internet market website

Application with animations, adaptive layout, list of phones, tablets and accessories, sliders, pagination, filtering, sorting, routing, authorization, dark and white themes and other interesting features.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>Github</u>

#### Bicycle shop landing page

One-page adaptive landing page with a mobile menu, various sections, blocks, and cards.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>GitHub</u>

#### Task manager application

A well-styled task manager with the ability to add, delete, mark tasks as completed, switch between completed and active tasks, mark all as completed, and delete all completed tasks. The application also operates using an API where all tasks are stored.

• <u>Demo</u> • <u>GitHub</u>

#### **Courses landing**

One-page adaptive landing page with a mobile menu, various sections, blocks, and cards. There are also two different sliders and pagination here.

• Demo • Github

# **ADDITIONAL EDUCATION**

### Mate Academy Apr 2023 - Oct 2023

- Learned advanced features of the layout, <u>JavaScript</u>, <u>TypeScript</u>, <u>React</u>, <u>Redux</u>, and <u>Node.js</u>
- Gained knowledge about <u>How the Web Works (OSI model, HTTP, Encryption, API Interface, and Security in the Web)</u>
- Learned about Algorithms and Data Structures
- Got <u>SQL Basics knowledge</u>

# HYS Academy Front-End Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

- Learned how to create web page <u>markup</u>, <u>stylize</u> a web page, and make it <u>responsive</u> for different screen extensions
- Learned how to create a web page using the <u>mobile-first method</u> and work with the <u>SCSS</u> preprocessor. Additionally, I learned about <u>Figma</u>, a web service for designing user interfaces
- Gained experience in bundling projects using Webpack and correctly typing code using TypeScript
- Worked on two pet projects, one of which utilized the Angular framework and the RxJS library
- Learned how to interact with servers and understand how web APIs work

#### Coursor Education Dec 2021 - Feb 2022

- Learned <u>JavaScript</u>, including variables, data types and their uses, operators, conditional statements, loops, functions, objects, and more
- Gained knowledge of the working principles of <u>Webpack</u>, which can be used to assemble projects in a high-quality manner
- Gained experience working with the <u>React</u>library and mastered its basic concepts. Lastly, I became familiar with the <u>Redux</u> state manager

# **EDUCATION**

University: Odesa National Law Academy 2014 - 2020

Degree: Master's Degree in Law

Civil and Economic Justice Faculty 2017 - 2018

Course of lectures and seminars in Law in English